vectary.com 2017-06-06

# VECTARY - the free, online 3D modeling software

#### Effective Date: October 20, 2016

By using the Site and/or Services of Vectary, Inc. (Company, we or us) (and/or by accepting our Terms of Use) you agree with the terms and conditions of this Privacy Policy (Privacy Policy) that will apply regarding the privacy practices of the website located at [www.vectary.com](https://www.vectary.com/) (the Site). This Privacy Policy does not apply to information we collect by other means (including offline) or from other sources.

### 1\. INTERPRETATION

  * 1.1 All the capitalized terms used in this Privacy Policy shall have the meaning assigned to them in our Terms of Use.

### 2\. INFORMATION WE COLLECT

2.1 We collect and process your personal data in the following instances (Data): 

    * (a) information that you provide to us when registering with our Site (including your name, email address and password);
    * (b) potentially personally identifiable information about your computer and about your visits to and use of our Site and/or Services (including your IP address and geographical location, browser type and version, operating system, referral source, length of visit, page views and website navigation paths or any similar information that may be obtained by the Company directly or indirectly from third party providers);
    * (c) information that you provide when completing your profile on our Site (including your name, profile pictures, gender, date of birth, interests and hobbies, educational details and employment details, description, tags);
    * (d) information that you provide to us for the purpose of subscribing to our email notifications and/or newsletters (including your name and email address);
    * (e) information that you provide to us when using our Site and/or the Services, or that is generated in the course of the use of those Services (including the timing, frequency and pattern of Service use);
    * (f) information relating to any purchases you make in respect of the Services (including your name, address, telephone number, email address and payment card details, bank account details);
    * (g) information that you post to our Site for publication on the internet;
    * (h) information contained in or relating to any communication that you send to us or send through our Site (including the communication content and metadata associated with the communication); and
    * (i) any other personal information that you choose to send to us.
2.2 Our Site uses cookies. 
    * (a) A cookie is a file containing an identifier (a string of letters and numbers) that is sent by a web server to a web browser and is stored by the browser. The identifier is then sent back to the server each time the browser requests a page from the server.
    * (b) Cookies may be either "persistent" cookies or "session" cookies: a persistent cookie will be stored by a web browser and will remain valid until its set expiry date, unless deleted by the user before the expiry date; a session cookie, on the other hand, will expire at the end of the user session, when the web browser is closed.
    * (c) Cookies do not typically contain any information that personally identifies a user, but personal information that we store about you may be linked to the information stored in and obtained from cookies.
    * (d) We use both session and persistent cookies on our Site and/or with respect of our Services.
    * (e) Please acknowledge that blocking and/or deleting cookies will have a negative impact upon the usability of the Site and/or our Services.

### 3\. CONSENT

  * 3.1 By submitting your Data through our Site and/or the Services, you agree to the terms of this Privacy Policy and you expressly consent to the collection, use, and disclosure of your Data in accordance with this Privacy Policy.

### 4\. HOW WE USE YOUR DATA

  * 4.1 We may use your Data for the purpose of proper exercise of your rights and obligations under the Terms of Use and in relation to your use of our Site and/or Services. We also use the Data you submit to operate, maintain, and provide the features and functionality of the Site and to respond to questions or requests you have submitted to us.
  * 4.2 Any personal information or content that you voluntarily disclose for posting to the Site, its related forums, message boards, your Public Projects, or similar publicly accessible areas or content become available to the public. We are not responsible for personally identifiable information and data contributions that you choose to disclose publicly in these areas. If you remove information that you posted, copies may remain viewable in cached and archived pages, or if other users have copied or saved that information.
  * 4.3 By providing us your email address, you consent to our using the email address to send you service-related notices, including any notices required by law, in lieu of communication by postal mail. We may also use your email address to send you other messages, such as newsletters, changes to Services, or special offers. If you do not want to receive such messages, you may unsubscribe by following the link provided in the email communication. Unsubscribing may prevent you from receiving messages regarding updates, improvements, or offers. You may not unsubscribe from service-related emails. If you correspond with us by email, we may retain the content of your email messages and our responses.
  * 4.4 We may use certain information about you and/or certain of your data without identifying you as an individual to third parties. We do this for purposes such as analyzing how the Site is used, diagnosing service or technical problems, maintaining security, and personalizing content. We may work with analytics companies such as Google Analytics and Localytics to help us understand how the Site is being used, such as the frequency and duration of usage, how users found our Site, and other non-personally identifiable information so we can deliver a better experience and improve the Site.
  * 4.5 We reserve the right, but have no obligation, to monitor the information you post on the Site and related forums. If applicable, we reserve the right to remove any such information or material for any reason or no reason, including without limitation if in our sole opinion such information or material violates, or may violate, any applicable law or to protect or defend our rights or property or those of any third party. We also reserve the right to remove information upon the request of any third party.

### 5\. HOW WE SHARE YOU DATA

  * 5.1 We may disclose your Data to any of our employees, contractors, officers, insurers, professional advisers, agents, suppliers or subcontractors, member of our group of companies insofar as reasonably necessary for the purposes set out in this Privacy Policy.
  * 5.2 We may disclose your personal information:
    * (a) to the extent that we are required to do so by law;
    * (b) in connection with any ongoing or prospective legal proceedings; or
    * (c) in order to establish, exercise or defend our legal rights (including providing information to others for the purposes of fraud prevention and reducing credit risk).
  * 5.3 Personally Identifiable Information: We may share your personally identifiable information with third parties solely for the purpose of providing services to you, including for the processing of financial transactions as set forth in Section 9 below. We may store personal information in locations outside our direct control (for instance, on servers or databases co-located with hosting providers).
  * 5.4 We do not share your personally identifiable information or personally-identifiable location information with third-party companies for their direct marketing use. As we develop our business, we may buy or sell assets or business offerings. User email and visitor information is generally one of the transferred business assets in these types of transactions. We may also transfer such information in the course of corporate divestitures, mergers, or dissolution.
  * 5.5 Non-Personally Identifiable Information: We may share non-personally identifiable information (such as anonymous usage data, referring/exit pages and URLs, platform types, number of clicks, etc.) with interested third parties to help them understand the usage patterns for certain services.
5.6 We may allow third-party ad servers or ad networks to serve advertisements on the Site. These third-party ad servers or ad networks use technology to send, directly to your browser, the advertisements and links that appear on the Site. They automatically receive your IP address when this happens. They may also use other technologies (such as cookies, JavaScript, or web beacons) to measure the effectiveness of their advertisements and to personalize the advertising content. We do not provide any personally identifiable information to these third-party ad servers or ad networks without your consent. However, please note that if an advertiser asks us to show an advertisement to a certain audience and you respond to that advertisement, the advertiser or ad-server may conclude that you fit the description of the audience they are trying to reach. This Privacy Policy does not apply to, and we cannot control the activities of, third-party advertisers. Please consult the respective privacy policies of such advertisers for more information. 
  * 5.7 Except as provided in this Privacy Policy, we will not provide your personally identifiable information to third parties.

### 6\. DURATION

  * 6.1 We shall be authorized to process your Data during the time when you continue to use our Site and/or Services (that includes the whole time when your registration at our Site is valid).
  * 6.2 We shall be also authorised to process your Data after you stop using our Site and/or Services, if it is necessary to
    * (a) meet our legal obligations; or
    * (b) establish, exercise or defend our legal rights (including providing information to others for the purposes of fraud prevention and reducing credit risk).

### 7\. RIGHTS AND OBLIGATIONS

  * 7.1 We shall process your Data in accordance with applicable law and protect your Data against misuse and/or any unlawful disclosure.
  * 7.2 Data shall be processed by us in our internal information system called VECTARY admin.
  * 7.3 You further acknowledge that you provide us your consent voluntarily and you can withdraw it at any time upon your discretion, however note, that you might not be able to use our Site and/or Services in such case (except for the withdrawal of consent described under Article 4.3 that will have no effect on your use of the Site and/or the Services).
  * 7.4 You acknowledge that your Data may be subject to cross-border transmission within the European Union and/or European Economic Area. Data that we collect may be stored and processed in and transferred between any of the countries in which we operate in order to enable us to use the information in accordance with this Privacy Policy.
  * 7.5 Data may be transferred to the following countries which do not have data protection laws equivalent to those in force in the European Economic Area: the United States of America, Russia, Japan, China and India.
  * 7.6 You hereby agree that we may provide and process your Data through third parties (hereby referred to as Subcontractors).
  * 7.7 Provided that you use the Site and/or Services and/or provide us with personal data of a third party (hereby referred to as the Relevant Person) you confirm and declare that you have the consent of the Relevant Person, in the form required by applicable law, for processing such personal data of Relevant Persons by us, at least in the extent provided in this Privacy Policy. You also confirm that you have fulfilled your information obligation towards the Relevant Person regarding the processing of personal data and their submission to us, including the information on cross-border transmission of information of personal data of the Relevant Person.

### 8\. CHILDREN’S PRIVACY

  * 8.1 Protecting the privacy of young children is especially important. For that reason, we do not knowingly collect or solicit personal information from anyone under the age of 13. If you are under 13, please do not send any information about yourself to us, including your name, address, telephone number, or email address. No one under age 13 is allowed to provide any personal information to or on the Site. In the event that we learn that we have collected personal information from a child under age 13 without verification of parental consent, we will delete that information as quickly as possible. If you believe that we might have any information from or about a child under 13, please contact us at [support@vectary.com](mailto:support@vectary.com).

### 9\. PROCESSING FINANCIAL TRANSACTIONS

  * 9.1 All the financial transactions process at our Site and/or in respect of the Services are handled through our payment services provider, Stripe and/or PayPal. You can review the provider's privacy policy at <https://stripe.com/privacypolicy> and/or at <https://www.paypal.com/sk/webapps/mpp/ua/privacy-full>. We will share information with our payment services provider only to the extent necessary for the purposes of processing payments you make via our Site, refunding such payments and dealing with complaints and queries relating to such payments and refunds.

### 10\. THIRD PARTY WEBSITES

  * 10.1 Our Site includes hyperlinks to, and details of, third party websites.
  * 10.2 We have no control over, and are not responsible for, the privacy policies and practices of third parties.

### 11\. MISCELLANEOUS

  * 11.1 You may, of course, decline to submit personally identifiable information through the Site, in which case we may not be able to provide the Services or access to the Site to you.
  * 11.2 Should you require any clarifications or additional information regarding personal data processing or protection please contact us via e-mail at [support@vectary.com](mailto:support@vectary.com)
  * 11.3 This Privacy Policy forms an integral part of the Terms of Use.
  * 11.4 Changes to Our Privacy Policy. If we change our privacy policies and procedures, we will post those changes on the Site to keep you aware of what information we collect, how we use it and under what circumstances we may disclose it. Changes to this Privacy Policy are effective when they are posted on the Site. Your use of the Site, and your continued use after we post a revised Privacy Policy, signifies your acceptance of the Privacy Policy and any revisions. It is therefore important that you review this Privacy Policy regularly to ensure you are updated as to any changes.
